Girish Chitale

501, Ramdas Niwas, Brahman fociety, Naupada, Thane - 400602

+91.9930956728 📞

girishce@gmail.com

Team lead with 9+ years of experience in implementing Windows, Citrix infrastructure aligned with security standards such as NIST, ISMS etc. Focused in Security Testing / Cloud Security / Citrix XenApp 6 & 6.5 / Windows Server 2008 R2 & 2012 network. Looking to leverage my knowledge and experience into a role as Project Manager.

Experience

JUNE 2019 - PRESENT

Team Leader - Application Support, EY GDS, MUMBAI

- Managing team and Providing software application support under the supervision of the Project Manager.
- Performing analyses on software application functionality and suggesting improvements.
- Ensuring effective front end and back end functionality of applications.
- Consulting with the software development team, internal users, and clients to improve application performance.
- Establishing the root causes of application errors and escalating serious concerns to the L3/L4 team.
- Keeping record of configuration changes and scheduling application updates.
- Documenting processes and monitoring application performance metrics.
- Providing front end support to clients and colleagues in other departments.

JANUARY 2015 - MAY 2019

Senior Systems Engineer, Thomson Reuters, Mumbai

JULY 2011 - DEC 2014

Systems Engineer, Thomson Reuters, Mumbai

- Monitoring for and reviewing new security vulnerabilities and emerging threats with the help of scan
- Managing compliance status of endpoint agents and Antivirus policies on servers and Endpoints.
- Strong knowledge on various type of attacks, malware, social engineering attacks, web application attacks, wireless attacks.
- Evaluate and prioritize risk and vulnerability for remediation and work with technical teams to carry out remediation.
- Notify client on probably reputational/operational risk that might affect the business and involve in drafting and implementing a Corrective Action Plan to mitigate the risk and follow up through to the point of resolution by working with the clients/business with the new controls and process plan.
- Maintain excellent rapport with the client and the management to discuss process improvements, risk and control identification with references to the issues and concern while testing.
- Experience in endpoint security with major Antivirus giants like McAfee ePO, McAfee VSE, McAfee Agent, Symantec Endpoint Protection, Trend Micro Deep Security and Trend Micro Office Scan in enterprise environment.
- Responsible to manage and maintain Citrix XenApp 6 & 6.5 farm
- Publishing applications/desktop in Citrix XenApp 6 & 6.5 and manage and maintain access for user.
- Handling Internal audits for ISMS/Cyber security.
- Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing for Network and Web applications.

- Have faced internal audits for ISMS and have knowledge of Risk Assessment and Treatment, Audit Checklist, ISMS policies and Procedures.
- Log monitoring, OSSIM configuration & Backup.
- Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing for Network and Web Application, Web Servers.
- Experience on Tools for Foot printing and Scanning like Nmap, Nikto, Owasp-Zap, Vega, Burp suit etc.

Key Projects Contributed To:

- Domain transitioning activities (April '19 June '19)
- XenApp 6.5 implementation for Texas users (Dec 2012 Jan 2013)
- XenApp 6.5 implementation for Eagan users (August 2015 Sept 2015). I've been to Eagan, MN (Sept '15 Oct '15) and Dallas, TX (Nov '15) for providing training to users to use citrix environment and ISMS.
- XenApp 6.5 implementation for Poland users (Jan 2016 Feb 2016)
- Datacenter Migration (May '15)

MAY 2010 - MAY 2011

Tech Support - L2, Wipro Infotech, Mumbai

- Responsible for Maintenance, installation, and Configuration of all Microsoft Windows, supporting for Windows based Systems, and regular Monitoring and updating critical Security and Antivirus patches for all Servers and Desktops, responsible for regular monitoring of all breakdown calls and submitting reports to the Management regularly.
- Server Support: Installation and configuration of servers (windows 2000/2003 server/Exchange server 2003), user management.
- Desktop Support: Providing support on Windows XP/windows 7 platforms on various kinds of problems related to OS/Applications/Network/Hardware etc., escalating the issues with various Vendors and to get the problem rectified within a short time and thus ensuring the No/less downtime for the End Users
- Supporting users in various office and troubleshooting their problem remotely using VNC/Remote Desktop Connection.

OCTOBER 2007 - AUGUST 2008

FMS Engineer, CMS Computers Ltd, Mumbai

Professional Certifications

Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH) v10 - 2018 ISO/IEC 27001:2005 LA - 2012 Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA) - 2009

Professional Skills

• Citrix XenApp 6 / 6.5 • Windows Server 2008 R2 / 2012 R2 • Office 365 • AWS • Azure • Nessus • OpenVAS • Burp Suit • Metasploit • Nmap • Wireshark • Acunetix

Skills

Analytical thinking • Planning • Strong Communication • Accuracy and attention to detail •
Organization and Prioritization • Problem Solving • Team Leadership

Education

JUNE 2009

Bachelor of Computer Science / University of Mumbai, Chiplun

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 8th March 1986

Languages Known: English, Marathi, Hindi

• Nationality: Indian

■ Sex: Male

Marital Status: Single